杭州市二零二三年初中学业水平考试。
and secondary exams.
第一节，听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
B, All the t -shirts are over there.
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
The large t are on the right.
Did you have a good day at school, Fred?
It was okay, apart from history.
That was boring as usual.
But luckily, that was in the morning.
And in the afternoon, we had science.
That was lots of fun.
But you weren't there.
Oh, I went to see my grandparents.
Will someone meet you at the airport,
Yes, of course.
It's a long way home.
I think Mum's working, but Dad can pick me up.
Oh, that's alright then.
Was the weather good for your camping trip?
I'm afraid not.
There was no rain, but there was a lot of wind.
Oh, that's a pity.
I know. But at least it was not cold.
听下面一段对话，回答第六至第八三个小题。
现在。哎，你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题
Thank you. Olivia, are you free tomorrow evening?
Monday evening? No, I'm not.
I'm seeing a friend.
But I'm free on Tuesday evening.
Great. Let's do something together on Tuesday then.
Good idea. What do you want to do?
How about going to the movies?
There aren't any good movies on at the moment.
Why don't we go swimming instead?
That's a great idea.
Let's meet in front of my house.
Okay. At what time?
How long does it take to get there?
It takes about 30 minutes.
Is 7.30 okay?
Yes, that's fine.
See you then.
Olivia, are you free tomorrow evening?
Monday evening? No, I'm not.
I'm seeing a friend.
But I'm free on Tuesday evening.
Great. Let's do something together on Tuesday then.
Good idea. What do you want to do?
How about going to the movies?
There aren't any good movies on at the moment.
Why don't we go swimming instead?
That's a great idea.
Let's meet in front of my house.
Okay. At what time?
How long does it take to get there?
It takes about 30 minutes.
Is 7.30 okay?
Yes, that's fine.
See you then.
听下面一段对话，回答第九至第十一三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
I just bought a ticket to New York City.
I'm so excited to see the city.
Good for you.
Travelling is so much fun.
I love discovering new places and new people.
When are you leaving?
Next Monday. I'm taking the Red Eye.
It was cheaper.
Hopefully I'll be able to sleep on the plane.
I wish I could go with you.
New York City is a magical place.
You will have so much fun.
I hope so.
I'm going to visit my brother who lives there.
I will stay for a week and then take the train down to Washington D.C.
That sounds like a great vacation.
I'm looking forward to a week at the beach in San Francisco for my summer vacation.
I just want to relax.
I just bought a ticket to New York City.
I'm so excited to see the city.
for you. Travelling is so much fun.
I love discovering new places and new people.
When are you leaving?
Next Monday. I'm taking the Red Eye.
It was cheaper.
Hopefully I'll be able to sleep on the plane.
I wish I could go with you.
New York City is a magical place.
You will have so much fun.
I hope so.
I'm going to visit my brother who lives there.
I will stay for a week and then take the train down to Washington D.C.
That sounds like a great vacation.
I'm looking forward to a week at the beach in San Francisco for my summer vacation.
I just want to relax.
听下面一段。
读白，回答第十二至第十五四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
It's really exciting to be here to talk about my writing.
I've been writing stories since I was about eight years old.
My parents always read to me and I learned to read myself quite early when I was
four. So I've been in love with books for a long time.
I started inventing stories to read to my friend on the school bus.
He loved them.
Then I sent one in to a competition because my teacher suggested it.
I won second prize and my story appeared in a magazine.
I was so proud.
People ask me where I usually write.
I used to write in the school library, but these days I've got a study where I can
either be quiet or play music if I want to.
Another question I am often asked is about where my ideas for stories come from.
Some writers keep a notebook where they write down interesting things they see or
hear about. I started doing that, but my notebook was never with me when I wanted
it. So I have notes on my phone.
That's usually with me.
Now, are there any questions?
It's really exciting to be here to talk about my writing.
I've been writing stories since I was about eight years old.
My parents always read to me and I learned to read myself quite early when I was
four. So I've been in love with books for a long time.
I started inventing stories to read to my friend on the school bus.
He loved them.
Then I sent one in to a competition because my teacher suggested it.
I won second prize and my story appeared in a magazine.
I was so proud.
People ask me where I usually write.
I used to write in the school library, but these days I've got a study where I can
either be quiet or play music if I want to.
Another question I am often asked is about where my ideas for stories come from.
Some writers keep a notebook where they write down interesting things they see or
hear about. I started doing that, but my notebook was never with me when I wanted
it. So I have notes on my phone.
That's usually with me.
Now, are there any questions?